Preliminary Inventory of the Andrew Romanoff papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Andrew Romanoff papers
1870-1994
2016C42
Hoover Institution Archives
1 manuscript box, 1 oversize box (2.4 linear feet)
Correspondence, printed matter, personal documents, photographs, and memorabilia, relating to the House of Romanov.
Romanoff, Andrew,
Access
The collection is open for research. The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2016.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Historical note
Great-nephew of Tsar Nicholas II of Russia.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
Correspondence, printed matter, personal documents, photographs, and memorabilia, relating to the House of Romanov.
Romanov, House of.; Russia--History.
- Watercolor paintings and photographic prints and negatives, 1921-1925, undated (Folder 1: 1)
- Thirteen prints of various European royalty, undated (Folder 1: 2)
- Miscellaneous photographs, 1914-1928, undated (Folder 1: 3)
- Three passes issued to Grand Duchess Kseniia Aleksandrovna, 1922-1924 (Folder 1: 4)
- Miscellaneous clippings, 1954-1994, undated (Folder 1: 5)
- Letters addressed to Prince and Princess Romanoff, with related family correspondence, 1920-1957, undated (Folder 1: 6)
- Letters addressed to Prince Vasilii Romanov from Count Eric Lewenhaupt and Slobodan Beljanski, 1981-1982 (Folder 1: 7)
- Photocopies of Grand Duke Aleksandr Mikhailovich’s winery documents and Andrew Romanoff's baptismal certificate, 1919-1923 (Folder 1: 8)
- Menus and cards commemorating Russo-French visits to Kronstadt and Toulon, 1891-1938 (Folder 1: 9)
- Unidentified correspondence, 1870-1874 (Folder 1: 10)
- Two postcards adressed to Princess Kseniia in Belgium and Prince Galitzine in Denmark, one icon and one note, 1948, undated (Folder 1: 11)
- Letter addressed to “Grand Duke” from Fedor Filipov, 1920 (Folder 1: 12)
- Two letters and affidavit relating to Frideritzi-Sass-Ruffo, 1888-1918 (Folder 1: 13)
- Address from the Russo-Serbian Girl’s gimnaziia to Grand Duchess Kseniia Aleksandrovna, 1925 (Folder 1: 14)
- Chto dielat’?!, 1923 (Folder 1: 15)
- Miscellaneous books, pamphlets and periodical issues, 1842-1951 (Folder 1: 16-19)
- Decree of Nicholas II issued to Nikolai Bogoiavlenskii, Russian Consul at Nome, Alaska, 1913 September 2 (Folder 2: 1)
- Russkoe slovo, with special bulletin related to the abdication of Nicholas II, 1917 March 5-10 (Folder 2: 2-3)